CLASS 1 RIVER KARASUGAWA, GUNMA
（一级河川 乌川）
Kencho, Shizuka, have you heard of mindfulness?
阿宪、闲 你们听说过“正念”吗？
Immersing yourself in the present,
让自己沉浸在当下
and freeing yourself from the past and future, right?
摒除关于过去 和未来的一切杂念 对吧？
We went over it a lot in corporate seminars.
我们以前在企业研讨会上常干这个
That's right.
没错
I aspire to maintain that mindset at all times.
我希望自己能一直保持那样的心态
Listen, Akira. I'm going to give it to you straight.
阿辉 我跟你直说了吧
I don't think you need to do this.
其实你不用整这些
You're already there with your mindfulness or whatever.
就已经充满正念什么的了
27. TRY SUP YOGA
（27 尝试水上瑜伽）
Man, things are going great!
哇 进展很顺利呢！
I've got 15 out 100!
我的100个愿望已经实现了15个
I may be able to complete all 100 of them within a month!
也许不出一个月 我就能实现全部100个心愿了
I feel like you might get eaten by a zombie once you do.
總覺得你一旦实现所有心愿 就会被僵尸吃掉呢
How long until we get to your parent's place?
还要多久才能到你爸妈家呀？
About an hour, I suppose.
大概一个小时吧
That is if nothing happens, right?
前提是中途不出状况 对吧？
Do you know how many days it took for us to get here from Tokyo?
你知道我们从东京来到这里 花了多少天吗？
We just have to get there before the end of summer!
只要在夏天结束前赶到就好啦
What's going on?
怎么回事？
A survivor?
是有幸存者吗？
They lost a wheel and can't move!
那辆车有个轮胎脱落 动不了了
All right!
太棒了！
It's been a while, but it's time for my shark suit!
过了这么久 我的防鲨服是时候重出江湖喽
What? You're just gonna charge in there?
什么？你想冲进去吗？
Well, never mind.
好吧 当我没说
Stop right there, you zombies!
住手 你们这些僵尸！
I won't let you do whatever you want anymore!
我不会再放任你们为所欲为了
Superhero of Justice, Akiraiger, is here--
代表正义的超级英雄 辉狮虎侠在此…
SLASH
（斩）
CHOP
（劈）
SHOOT
（射箭）
CROSSBOW
（连弩）
KILLING
（诛杀）
KILLING FIELD
（血腥战场）
What's this? Are we in a period drama?
什么情况？ 我们穿越到某个时代剧里了吗？
That's so cool!
太酷啦！
Danke schön.
万分感谢
I owe you all a debt of gratitude for your assistance.
承蒙襄助 我欠各位一个人情
What?
什么？
My name is Beatrix Amerhauser.
我是贝雅托里斯·阿默豪瑟
A foreigner?
一个外国人？
A girl?
是个小姐姐？
I don't even know where to begin.
我都不知该作何感想了
So, Beatrix, you came here from Germany because you're a big fan of Japan?
所以说 贝雅托里斯你是因为 喜爱日本才从德国远道而来？
Ja!
对！
Nippon's culture is so wonderful!
日本的文化真的很美妙
Kyoto, Fujiyama, tea ceremony, ikebana…
京都、富士山、茶道、花道…
I love this country, so I've studied all of them a lot.
我全都研习过 我爱这个国家
So that explains the Japanese armor.
难怪你会穿着武士铠甲了
That said, it's not a bad anti-zombie strategy.
话说回来 这个做为防僵尸的策略还不错呢
Refrigeration.
这是冷藏库？
Fish?
鱼？
I have reasons to deliver this fish.
我因为某些原因 必须把这些鱼送去一个地方
That is not possible anymore.
但现在做不到了
Seeing that you are all brave samurai, I have a request!
既然诸位都是英勇的武士 我有一个请求！
Would you please help me deliver this fish to Takasaki?
请帮助我把这些鱼送去高崎市
I suppose we could stop by Takasaki, but…
我们是可以顺道 去一趟高崎市啦 不过…
If she's transporting food to survivors, shouldn't we help?
如果她要给幸存者送食物 我们理应帮忙不是吗？
Even so, considering the risks of going near a city…
话虽如此 但考虑到靠近城市的风险…
Why do you want to transport that fish so badly?
你为什么这么想运送那些鱼？
Ever since I was exposed to Nippon's culture on TV as a child,
自从小时候在电视上 接触到日本文化的那一刻起
I've dreamed of coming here.
我就一直梦想着来这里
I worked many jobs saving up money, but the morning I landed in Narita,
为此我努力打工攒钱 但飞机降落在成田机场的那天早上
the pandemic was already…
僵尸病毒就已经爆發
The beautiful Nippon I dreamed of was gone.
我魂牵梦萦的美丽日本 已经不复存在了
But after admiring Nippon's culture for so many years,
但是对日本文化仰慕了这么多年
I just had to see it and experience it for myself.
我必须亲眼见证和体验一番
And at last, I found it!
终于 我找到了机会
The last surviving sushi chef!
我发现了幸存的最后一位寿司师傅！
Sushi?
寿司？
The taisho of this sushi-ya told me that if I could deliver fish to him,
那家寿司店的大厨告诉我 只要我把鱼送去给他
he would let me have my fill of delicious sushi!
他就会让我尽情享用美味的寿司！
-She's just in it for sushi?!
-她送鱼只是为了吃寿司？
Beatrix.
贝雅托里斯
It's clear to me that your love of Japanese culture is pure and true.
我明白了 你对日本和日本文化 充满了真挚纯粹的热爱
Regarding that fish…
至于那些鱼…
We'll deliver it to that sushi place in Takasaki even if it costs us our lives!
哪怕要付出生命的代价 我们也一定 会把它送到高崎市的寿司店！
-He's only in it for the sushi too!
他送鱼也只是为了吃寿司！
Danke schön! You are a true samurai!
万分感谢！你是一名真正的武士
Now that that's decided, let's hurry, you two!
既然决定了 就赶快行动吧 你们两个！
The fish is losing quality every second we stand around!
我们在这里每耽搁一秒 鱼的品质都会下降
It's time to show her the spirit of hospitality!
是时候向她展现东道主的热情了
-Yeah.
-对 -好
The sushi-ya is down an alleyway past Central Ginza.
寿司店坐落在中央银座的一条小巷里
A back alley! I get the feeling this place has a long history!
在后巷！我有预感 这是一家历史悠久的店
TAKASAKI CENTRAL GINZA
（高崎 中央银座）
I get the feeling that it's a famous place!
感觉它一定是很有名的餐厅！
But the last time I talked to him over the phone was over three days ago.
但我最后一次跟大厨通电话 已经是三天前的事了
I sure hope the taisho is all right.
希望他仍然平安无事
How many of them are there?
这里到底有多少僵尸啊？
Shall we get going, Beatrix?
贝雅托里斯 我们上吧！
Okay, Akira!
好的 阿辉！
Well, it's nice that you're motivated, but do you have some sort of plan?
像这样充满斗志是很好啦 但你们做好了计划吗？
-Nope! -Nein!
-没有！ -并未！
Is charging in head first the only thing they can think of?
他俩就只能想到一头冲进去吗？
-I might have a plan. -What?
-在下或有一计 -什么？
"All under heaven is not for one man, but for all men."
“天下者 乃天下人之天下 非一人之天下”
If we're going to do this, we will all pig out on delicious sushi!
事已至此 不妨一同饱餐美味的寿司吧
We're doing Three Kingdoms now?
这是在玩《三国志》角色扮演吗？
Hey! This way, you zombies!
喂！看这边 僵尸！
What do you think of this tasty piece of ass?! Get a bite, if you can!
这个秀色可餐的屁屁怎么样？ 有本事来咬一口呀
This way!
这边！
Come on!
来啊！
Now, Akira!
快动手 阿辉！
Beatrix!
贝雅托里斯！
Please leave this to me.
尽管交给在下吧
INVINCIBLE
（天下无双）
Shizuka, I've rounded up as many as I could!
闲 我已经把殭尸 都尽可能聚集过来了
-Are you ready? -Of course.
-你准备好了吗？ -当然
It is just as I planned.
一切尽在掌握之中
All right!
好的
The time has come!
时候到了！
Now! Unleash the flames!
动手！放火！
-Okay! -Time for a barbecue!
-好！ -烧烤时间到！
Hey, isn't this a bit too many?
僵尸的数量有点太多了吧？
Hurry up and light the fire!
快点火
-Okay! -Ja!
-好 -好的
What?
什么？
This match doesn't want to light.
这个火柴点不燃
Hurry!
快啊！
This is bad.
糟了
At this rate, our RV will be buried in zombies!
照这样下去 我们的露营车会被僵尸淹没的
No way.
不行
If that happens, the fish we transported will be…
那样的话 我们带来的鱼就会…
We can't fight that many.
可是那么多僵尸 我们打不过的
It's all over!
全完了
Fear…
恐惧
is just an excuse not to act.
只是坐以待毙之人的借口
It's not about whether we can or can't.
重点不在于能否做到
It's about whether we have a burning desire to want to do it!
而在于我们是否 有想要去做的强烈愿望
-He just wants to eat sushi.
-他只是想吃寿司而已
If we can't eat at a nice sushi restaurant,
都到了这一步 如果不能在高档寿司店大吃一顿
I'd rather become a zombie!
还不如被僵尸吃掉呢！
Incoming!
看招！
Oshite mairu!
接招吧！
Beatrix!
贝雅托里斯
I'm sorry about my shameful behavior earlier.
我为刚才的可耻想法道歉
I will no longer waver.
我再也不会动摇了
-Let's do this, Akira! -Okay!
-上吧 阿辉 -好
-Akira! -Leave it to me!
-阿辉！ -交给我！
Why you…
怎么会…
They just keep coming!
不停有僵尸围上来
Akira, at this rate…
阿辉 照这样下去…
That's my Walkman!
那是我的随身听
And we'll do this.
就这么办吧
What are you going to use it for?
你想用它来做什么？
We don't know what'll happen, so we should prepare a backup plan.
作为备用计划 以防有意想不到的状况发生
This is…
这是…
The zombies are…
这些僵尸…
They're being lured away!
僵尸被引开了！
I didn't want to do this because it would cause more damage,
我本不愿出此下策 以免造成不必要的损失
but I guess I have no choice, do I?
但眼下我别无选择 不是吗？
Once again, the time has come.
再一次 时候到了
Unleash the flame!
放火！
Yeah!
好耶！
Tonight we're pigging out on fancy all-you-can-eat sushi!
我们今晚要在 高档寿司店大吃一顿啦！
DAIGINZUSHI SUSHI
（大银鮨寿司）
Delicious!
太好吃啦！
What the hell is this?
这太厉害了吧？
I don't even have to chew. It just melts in my mouth!
入口即化 都不用我嚼
The vinegared rice gently falls apart in my mouth.
融合了醋香的米饭在嘴里轻轻散开
And it's prepared with such care. I have no complaints about this sushi.
如此精心准备的美食 这个寿司真是无可挑剔
It's firm and has the right amount of sweetness.
肉质紧实 略带恰到好处的甜味
I've never eaten anything like this, even when entertaining clients in Ginza!
我连在银座招待客户时 也没吃过如此美味的寿司
I may have moved back home to Gunma,
虽然搬回了群马老家
but I've been honing my skills for about thirty years in Tsukiji!
我这可是在筑地 打磨过三十年的厨艺呢
You came to eat my sushi even at the end of the world!
哪怕到了世界末日 你们还愿意冒险来品尝我做的寿司
Eat as much as you like today!
今天请你们尽情享用吧
Perhaps I'll try the gizzard shad next!
接下来我要尝尝亮皮鱼！
Another bottle of cold sake!
再来一瓶冰镇清酒
So tasty! It's so tasty that I could keep eating this forever!
太美味了 让我吃一辈子都行
Nice sushi restaurants are the best!
高档寿司店果然是最棒的！
How is it, Beatrix?
怎么样 贝雅托里斯？
It's bitter.
好咸哪
Bittersweet, but delicious.
虽然咸 但是很美味
I'm really happy to be here!
能来到这里 我真的很幸福！
Welcome to Japan!
欢迎来日本！
I can't believe you're shedding tears over my sushi.
真不敢相信 你吃我做的寿司竟然感动哭了
I worked every day, without any days off,
我每天都在工作 从不间断
even on my daughter's wedding day and on the day my wife died.
哪怕在女儿的婚礼当天 或者妻子去世那天也不例外
I've never felt so honored as a chef.
身为厨师 我从来没有这么自豪过
You guys are probably my last customers.
你们也许是我最后一批顾客了
Tonight, you can drink all the sake in the restaurant!
今晚 本店的所有清酒 可以任你们畅饮！
Are you serious, Taisho?
真的吗 师傅？
You're so generous!
您真是太豪爽啦
7. PIG OUT AT A NICE SUSHI RESTAURANT
（七 在高档寿司店大吃一顿）
So, this is one of Nippon's heat waves.
这就是日本的猛暑日啊？
They are not to be underestimated.
真是不可小觑呢
We haven't had a proper bath in days now.
我们已经很多天没好好洗个澡了
Bathing in a river just makes us smell swampy.
在河里洗澡 身上总有一股泥水味
I just want to bathe in some pristine hot water once in a while.
我有时也想用乾淨的热水洗洗澡呀
With that said…
既然如此
We're going to a hot spring!
我们去泡温泉吧！
16. KICK BACK IN A HOT SPRING
（16 泡温泉放松）
-Amazing!
-太棒啦！
-Hot water fields are amazing!
温泉田超酷呀
I knew it.
果然
I fear it may fall out even with the men's robe.
跟我担心的一样 就算穿男士浴袍 胸部还是包不住
I wish I had your problems.
这种烦恼真令人羡慕
You both look splendid!
你们两人都很漂亮
When I worked at that exploitative company every hour of the day,
我在那家黑心企业没日没夜地工作时
I never dreamed of taking a vacation like this!
做梦都不敢想象能有如此完美的假期
So, this is a hot spring town!
原来这就是温泉小镇呀！
Most European cities are built around a town square.
大多数欧洲城市 都是围绕着城镇广场建立的
But you only see that in hot spring towns in Japan, so it's a very rare sight.
但这种景象在日本却很少见 只有在温泉小镇才会看到
They are built around the gushing hot springs!
城镇围绕着喷涌的温泉而建
I see. As usual, you're quite knowledgeable, aren't you?
原来如此 你果然很博学呢
Kusatsu Hot Spring was always at the top
草津温泉可是一直位列
of the National Hot Spring Efficacy Record,
江户和明治时代之间
which was published between the Edo and the Meiji period.
公布的国家温泉功效排名的榜首呢
She knows more about Japan than any Japanese person.
她真是比日本人还要了解日本
They claimed they could cure everything but love sickness.
据说这温泉能治愈一切伤痛 唯独无法抚平相思
They also drew visitors from all over the country!
全国各地都有游客慕名前来呢
Everything but love sickness?
唯独无法抚平相思吗？
Then hopping in one won't cure my feelings for Bea!
那就算跳进温泉 也没法消除我对贝雅你的爱慕喽？
Love?
相思吗？
Normally, this would've been a good place to go on a date.
通常情况下 这里应该是约会时来才对
Sorry you're stuck with us.
真抱歉 现在只有我们陪你了
Dating is a waste of time and resources for what amounts to temporary pleasure.
约会的本质就是 为了片刻欢愉而浪费时间和资源
Your 20s are better spent acquiring the knowledge and skills
20多岁的年轻人 不如把那些时间用来学习知识和技能
to get promotions and earn more money.
努力升职加薪 也能赚更多的钱
You can think about whether you need a partner once you've done that.
等事业成功之后 再考虑自己是否需要伴侣也不迟
That sounds like something you would say, Shizuka.
听起来确实像是你会说的话呢 闲
But for me, life would be more fun with someone I liked,
但我认为跟喜欢的人在一起 生活会更有乐趣
and I feel like that way I would work harder too.
而且我觉得 那样我会更有动力去努力打拼呢
How ridiculous.
真是荒谬
You might fall for someone who doesn't love you back
你付出的爱有可能得不到回应
or become the object of affection of someone you don't like.
你也可能被不喜欢的人迷恋
Love is an investment with poor cost performance.
爱情就是一项低性价比的投资
An utter waste of time.
纯粹是浪费时间
LARGE OPEN-AIR BATH
（大型露天温泉浴池）
-A large open-air bath! It's huge!
-大型露天温泉浴池！好大呀！
I'm going first!
我先下去！
Hold on!
等一下！
Weren't you going to kick back in a hot spring?
你们不是要泡温泉放松的吗？
But I guess I can finally wash away all the grime!
不过 我终于可以 洗掉身上的汗水了！
Let's leave the boys and head to the women's bath!
别管这两个男生了 我们快去女士浴池吧！
Shizuka, this thing is, there's no hot water in the women's bath.
闲 问题是 女士浴池里没有热水
-What? -It appears the pump isn't working.
-什么？ -好像是水泵坏了
You're joking, right?
开什么玩笑？
So, then, the only hot spring is this men's bath?
所以说 镇上只有 这个男士浴池才有温泉了？
These are extreme circumstances.
现在是极端情况
Desperate times call for desperate measures.
非常时期需采取非常手段
There's no need to be ashamed.
不用害羞
-Come join-- -Intolerable, obscene, revolting.
-加入… -难以容忍、下流、令人作呕
Every fiber of my being is repulsed by you.
我身上的每一个毛孔 都对你们感到厌恶
You're wrong about that, Shizuka.
你错了 闲
Since ancient times, this country has had a…
从古代起 这个国家就有…
In other words, let us not be ashamed!
换句话说 我们不用害羞！
Konyoku bathing is a proud cultural and historical practice from Nippon!
男女混浴 是日本的优良文化和传统习俗！
-Thank you for loving our culture!
-谢谢你对我们文化的热爱！
There are so many of them!
好多僵尸啊！
This means we won't be able to kick back at a hot spring!
也就是说 我们不能在温泉里放松享受了
What a let down!
真扫兴！
I wanted to visit all the famous places!
我还想打卡所有著名景点呢！
Just when Bea was about to bathe with us!
贝雅刚才要跟我们鸳鸯浴的呀
Damn it! Damn it all!
可恶！太讨厌啦！
I don't think we can make it back to the car.
感觉我们没法回到车上了
We just have to pray that they'll eventually go away.
只能祈祷僵尸们自行散开了
That aside, what about the hot spring?
先别管那个了 温泉怎么办呀？
I still haven't got to kick back at all!
我还完全没享受到呢！
At least you got to soak in one for a little while!
你至少已经泡了一小会儿了
I wanted to wash away my grime, too!
我也想洗白白呀！
I'm thirsty.
我好口渴
The sound of water?
有水声？
Amazing.
太神奇了
There's a hot spring in the middle of the mountains.
在深山里居然有一汪温泉
This seriously feels great.
感觉太棒了
I bet heaven's got nothing on this!
天堂也不过如此了吧
Shizuka?
闲？
Sorry!
对不起！
I seriously didn't know you were there! It really was an accident!
我真的不知道你在这里！ 这真的只是个意外
I get it already. Hurry up and get out!
我知道了 你快出去！
What?
什么？
That's not fair!
这不公平
I wanted to kick back in a hot spring this whole time!
我一直都想在温泉里放松享受的呀
If I have to leave without getting in a hot spring after coming all this way,
如果大老远跑过来 连温泉都没泡就要走
I'd rather be eaten by zombies!
还不如被僵尸吃掉呢！
He really only cares about soaking in the hot spring.
他还真是只在乎泡温泉啊
In… that case…
这样的话…
Make sure you stay on the other side of the boulder!
你只能待在大石头的那一边 不准过来哦
Okay!
好！
-And if you turn around, you're dead! -Okay!
-要是敢转过来看我 你就死定了 -好！
About earlier…
之前的事
I'm sorry.
对不起
When I shot down your ideas about love…
我批判了你的爱情观
My father never approved of the way I lived my life.
我父亲从来都不认同我的生活方式
When your opinions are always ignored,
当个人意见从来都只会被忽略时
it makes it difficult to accept the opinions of others.
我开始变得很难接受别人的想法
In order to defend your position,
为了维护自己的立场
you assert your legitimacy by rejecting what others say.
我会通过否认他人的观点 来坚持自己是正确的
But you're not concerned about winning approval.
但你并不在乎能否得到别人的认同
You just say whatever comes to mind.
你总是那么心直口快
So it made me a little jealous and frustrated.
这让我有点嫉妒 又有点不甘心
And the old me slipped out.
不经意间变回了从前的我
The truth is I'm just bad at romance.
事实是 我根本不懂爱情
I'm afraid of getting hurt.
我害怕受伤害
That's why I said work was more important,
所以才说工作比爱情更重要
and I was just trying to act tough.
我只是在假装强悍而已
Shizuka, right now…
闲 现在的你
you're being very open.
就很坦率呀
If I ever fall in love,
如果有朝一日我会爱上某人
I hope it's with someone I can be this open with.
希望那是一个能让我如此坦率的人
Wait, what I said just now… I didn't mean it like that.
慢着 我刚才说的…我不是那个意思
Huh? Huh?
怎么会这样
So, does that mean…
所以 那是不是意味着…
There's a hot spring in the middle of the mountains!
大山深处有一汪温泉！
It's a noyu, a naturally occurring spring!
这就是来自大自然的天然涌泉呢
Since when did you two start hooking up?
你们两个什么时候开始勾搭上的？
No, wait, this is…
没有 等一下 这是…
It's not what you think!
不是你想的那样！
I wanted to soak in a hot spring too.
我也想泡温泉呀
How could you two go off by yourselves?!
你们怎么可以独自享受呢
I don't wanna be a third wheel but I won't forgive you for doing this behind my back!
我不想当电灯泡 但我绝不原谅你背着我偷偷来泡温泉
Let us soak in there too!
我们也要泡！
Stay out!
别过来！
This feels super great!
感觉太赞啦
Hot springs are the best!
温泉最棒了！
16. KICK BACK IN A HOT SPRING
（16 泡温泉放松）
Konyoku!
男女混浴！
I guess I have no choice.
真拿你们没辙
Next time: Treehouse of the Dead.
下一集：《死者的树屋》